We'll cover all the records given to me in the Mama City Council for Monday, May 6, 2020, for war.
And two, there's a proclamation declaring May 2024 as Aelers, Aelers, Dan Lowe's,
Syndrome and H.S.D. Awareness Month.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Third.
Motion to approve second.
Second.
Third.
Five.
Minutes from April 1st.
2020 four.
Regrimating in April 15.
Motion to approve?
Second.
office, the college owns Southwest Ward 3 in Dustin Pittman, Southwest Ward, are
the best of East Ward 4.
many or other valuable things, the performance for law performance, the performance of any
after duty pertaining to my office, other than the compensation allowed by law.
I further swear, I swear, I swear, I swear, I swear, I swear, I swear, I swear, I swear,
that I will faithfully discharge, that I will faithfully discharge, according to the Vest of my ability.
The duties of my office, the duties of my office, during such time as I am a member,
during such time as I am a member of the Myofacity Council of the Myamacity and the Board of Trustees of the Myofacity,
especially utility authority and city of Myano, the home of the family.
Thank you.
Hi, do I?
Go ahead.
So real quickly, for these two guys go, I just want to say thank you to both of them for serving our community.
A lot of times what we do up here, then you recognize we get a lot of the native calls and
late nights and away from our families, the meetings and stuff, so I appreciate you guys
to vote your time to it.
I don't know, I'm going to start for three years and we're glad to go over an empty seat, but finish that out.
So we appreciate both of you guys and thank you for starting our community.
Appreciate it.
You guys ready?
Yes.
Seven.
Letter of support from the City of Myano for the Department of Commerce Emergency Solutions grant
for the Community Crisis Center.
It is our yearly ask to be a community crisis center runs in 24-bed shelter here in town.
We rely on federal grants, local money, etc.
The emergency shelter grant provides a good portion.
Thank you.
use to operate the shelter. We just asked for a letter of support from the city. There is no
reporting or cost requirement to the city and all it is just a letter of support for our
continued operation. You guys do a great job for our community and we appreciate the service
you got to provide and I'm the others. You guys get used quite a bit for your services. So we do.
I know one of our council says you got a bit and I know he really enjoys what you guys do and he
do for. So I make a motion when you approve.
All right.
Hi.
Thank you for your support.
I guess we'll be able to take care of that.
If we submitted one, I have energy. I can in. I'll have a two tomorrow.
Thank you.
8.
Lunch and minute number 24 dash 14. Please department.
Experts and new revenues.
41,093 dollars and 20 cents received.
City manager moving general and administrative money is 69,600.
In the general fund to the capital improvements fund.
The purchase will come and turn by the authority property.
Today parcel number.
WR-1-72-95B.
Seruppose property section 29.
T28 and dash R23E.
Ottawa County Open Home.
Reserving amendment number 24 dash 12.
30,248 dollar 40 cents.
Wherein.
The biscuit year 23.
2223 and the biscuit year 2425.
Grant money is for the adult online high school grant.
We're transferred to the general fund to cover salaries.
Fire use in their county sales tax carryover.
About $1,000 to purchase new pages.
Repair pages.
And rescue truck tires.
What about that?
Another more.
Mayer, I want to point out that this.
This amendment doesn't include purchasing.
It's money for the purchase.
The property that you said the VOTA property.
So.
So we talked about new analysts because we know next fiscal year.
So this is the piece property where our welcome to my
Amazon is.
Now, but it's turn by.
This devolent sign.
It's a little triangle piece property there.
The VOTA was sort of buzzing.
So they offered us.
We're going to buy.
Keep our sign.
Step on there.
Motion to approve.
I'll second.
Hi.
Joe's.
Hitman.
Hi.
He's.
Parker.
Hi.
Here's.
The amendment.
24-18 moving funds from general fund to the MBRA fund.
Main Street and MRA.
Poland.
Cola.
Raise adjustments.
to cover over just in payroll accounts for each department.
This is something we do every year about April.
Lumpsums are budgeted in the two city manager,
trust managers, budgets, and then we balance it out in about April,
when people get, they get their marital colorases in July
and we wait until the end to about.
Most two approved.
We're 10 quarterly sales tax, and I find that's the part of our
statement of the.
So the quarterly sales tax, this is through April.
We get 3.65% sales tax, 3% goes to the general fund,
just to operate the general fund, which houses like the fire police,
parks, cemetery, those kind of departments.
And then the 0.65 goes to pay for the street and stadium
bonds for those bonds.
Those improvements.
So the 3% is at a little over $6 million as a
April.
We are up over last year, $168,692, which is about 2.89%.
Just for the new.
This is this year, the difference.
So I'm comparing last year to last year to kind of showing you what's going on.
And then I also compare to the best year, which since COVID,
it's always been the last year.
So the numbers are the same.
But sometimes it's not.
You know, we're seeing the numbers trend back down to normal percentages.
There's a lot of information on this page.
But one of the things is a 10 year average minus the COVID years,
the 3, what I call the COVID years.
So really, our sales tax increases about average of 0.78.
Every year you can see the growth sometimes it's a negative.
But it's about 0.78.
And like I said, this year is 2.89%.
So we're higher than we normally are.
And we expect that to pretty much continue just because of
inflation and people shopping locally.
So the next page is our use tax.
Use tax is used for capital improvements for the general fund.
We're at $9.414, which is we're up 18.25% over last year, which is great.
It was in FY 1819 that Amazon, the Amazon's of our year old, started paying use.
So that really jumped it up when you start seeing it this year right here. You start seeing it a pretty good significant increase in that
Another thing that happened I got a little note down here in August of 2015 the OTC no longer holds 1% they hold a half percent of that money
To collect the money for us, which is a great thing and then you can see our top categories here
The retail trade, wholesale trade and manufacturing, our 10 year average is 12.67 and down a little lower I've got a graph and it's just been that's
It's been crazy
The next page is just the 0.65 you'll see what goes to that particular fund, which has been number 116 to pay the street in stadium
Ons, same percentage, 36,000 over last year and again we're seeing it trimmed down you can see in years past that we had like one year we had a growth of sales tax at 16.74% that's crazy
And that's a COVID year so if you ever have questions shoot me an email copy a couple of your city manager and we'll all answer any questions you guys have
The next thing I would look at like the get is the finance statement, okay, so this is as of March because
Approving claims tonight finished at April so we don't have April membership, but this is through March
Normally every month we get about a 12th of our money in we spend about 12 which is kind of nice in most funds
We have 29 funds, you can see the number and the name each month be able to side
This column is already used, this column is our expenditures, anything highlighted are just things I like to point out
Again, we should be at about 75% of revenues for most
We are on essential spending to try to increase our carryover for next year and carryover is simply funds that's unused this year that just carries over next year
Essentially if we closed out our bank account, it's the money we would have to live in July
So we're trying to increase that we call carryover
The general fund has is at 76.85% and that is because our sales tax and has been really high this year
Which is great, also our inspections and permits have gone over budget in a good way for revenues
MSU A there at 70.82% we'd like to see that at 75 but some of the
The reasonings are solid waste or tipping fees, we're upside down with that when you
need to correct that, and then GRDA, they have a PPA that they pass, that they give,
that's our bill, and we pass it through as a PCA to our customers, and we estimated really
high, and it's two accounts, and the two accounts would equal $3 million, so we've only
collected a million of the three that we budgeted.
So that's why that is looking low.
However, when the PCA is, we don't get as much revenue for that, we're also not paying GRDA as
much, so it's offset by expenditures, it just looks crazy on there.
CBB fund, these three funds here are subsidized by their enterprise funds that are
subsidized.
CBB is a 53.01%.
We expect that the job pretty much, as you know, their busy season starts really.
They should be getting in a lot of revenue for the festival, and the eight man kind
of that.
So April should look a little different.
I'm assuming.
MDRA, they're just killing it.
They've had tons of theater rentals and confession sales.
That's why there's a so high airport fund.
I don't include the grant for the terminal because that kind of makes it crazy.
It makes them numbers crazy, so this is just their operating revenues and expenses, but
they're at 96.92%.
But the revenues are higher, and that's just because of their fuel sales have and
have gas and jet fuel.
The street and stadium bond, it's at 81.93, that is because of the sales tax.
It's going way over what we've budgeted.
Capital improvement, this is where we had the fire this time last April.
This is where the insurance checks are sitting, so until we spend them, they're going to
look like extra revenue.
We're going to spend them.
MIPFA, which is down here, the budget you've just approved, that is doing well.
They have a one-time lease that kind of makes it that excuse the number that they've gotten in
and then tower rent collections, or they find it to do a great job on collections and
they're in a real group, so that's helped in my PFA a lot.
MCFA, we've talked about this for several months now.
They're 114% well, they sold all their sweets, which is the first time ever.
Since 2013, we started in 2014, the hand had all the sweets sold.
Now they're all sold, and that's a big deal, and that's why it's over what they
budgeted.
The last thing I have, I don't have a page for this, but PCAX, so if you remember, go ahead.
You can't do 41 of demolishes, I thought I could even explain some stuff on that, but I was so high on it.
It gets money transferred in. It gets 50,000 from the MSUA every year.
And it invoices out when it builds people for demoing this better than me.
When you look at that, that's why I brought the actual breakdown news. Let's see.
Abatements, they're at 54%. They estimated they would build out $40,000 for abatements, and they just haven't.
Apparently, they have the abatements this year, so they're not hitting that for any reason.
We've had a lot. We just start collecting a little gas.
We've had a little gas. We've had a little gas.
We've had a little gas.
So what's the rate of course whenever we don't get paid for them?
Think you're along the property numbers taxes.
And then theoretically, the county will collect for us.
If they don't pay, it has to go on.
I think that's going for a little mercy on how much it's collected.
So they don't put the whole amount on that, but what they want?
No, they have to put the whole amount, but they don't know how to collect.
But they often don't collect anything.
If they do, does that come back to us?
If they do, it comes back to us.
That's a portion of share.
We've been fighting with the county.
We think they understand some things.
Because before they never did.
Well, they don't have law says no.
Well, we don't know yet.
We think that for the most part they are, they're not.
If they don't collect 100% of their taxes, they're owed.
They're as collect.
It's supposed to distribute it in percentage to not sure that they're in your stand.
They have to show us that they have the same percentage on what's owed to us as they're paying to the other entity.
It's the property, but a lot of times these properties are not even purchased at
top-shading the center, they have over a year, so they're counting to really the subject
to, you know, somebody's so crazy about what they're going to do, so they're going to
be met back for school.
If nobody buys the property at sale, then they can turn around and sell it.
These, most of these houses are the outside of the flood zone, or is it very?
No, but I can say that the majority of them is in the flood zone, and we have a, you know,
we've been, we've spent the last year and a half or so, and we've been, the FEMA Act was
in the middle of April, and just we finished it up this year, and it's likely through all that,
so we have a really picked up new home, houses, by the, you know, just for city birds, and we're
at, that it's typically, they are, that problem.
The PCA at Stormyery, back in February of 21, our usage for four days was two, basically, $2.7
million, and we paid that, the following October, and then we're collecting that from our
investor customers, they've all paid off, but now it's from the residential in general.
So as of the $2,120,000, $1,020,080, we have left to collect is $573,928,92, that is $78.73,
so you can close, and we've got 11.77 months approximately, not every month of the same, but about about
a year left to collect on that.
I just want to tell you, we do.
11.
The award-new elevator service contract C-24-14 decode incorporated for fiscal year, 2425,
recommended by staff and approve the contract upon the submission of all required contract
documents and authorized the amount of your sign that was due to seed.
Council and Mayor, we sent out bids to multiple elevator service companies and we only received
one elevator service bid, and you can see here under routine maintenance, what the charges
are, and then non-Routine emergency and so on.
What it comes down to, if you just kind of get it right down to the small details, it's
about a $17 monthly increase for routine maintenance at the Civic Center in the Library
and about a $30 or an increase per month for a current contract with Co-Nate, and it's
our, it's the staff recommendation that Co-Nate is accepted, and we ask for your approval.
And we also, again, on this one, we have a possibility of three, one year extensions, and we'll keep
an eye on it.
Co-Nate's been a very good service company for us.
Thank you.
12.
The award-new annual on call as needed electrical electric electric and service contract C-24S-16HK
electric, input and booth for fiscal year 2425 is recognized by staff and approve the contract
upon the submission of all required contract documents and authorized the City Manager sign
in the nose to proceed.
The same will be approved in the MSUA.
We have to do the council's will.
Let's do a perm.
Second.
Hi.
Jo, hi.
Goodman.
Hi.
13.
Parts of new extraction, constriction.
constrictation.
Extracautions.
Tools.
Just put the dolls live on our way to the museum.
From casco industries in the amount of $55,177 dollars.
So if you remember a couple weeks ago at the meeting, we talked about it.
Thank you.
to get parts to things because this approval will let us reflect all of our
application. New battery powered. Motion to approve.
Questions have a question.
I wish what's the life expected to see on these service requirements?
What do you guys get?
We get this part of this contact comes with X-Fact. How long did we have the ones we are
replacing?
And the last track I went to, they still were pretty good, but they was growing a little
bit.
It's a little worse.
So these tools are the newest.
No electrics.
No alarm.
No hoses and hydraulic motor.
Do that again.
Thank you.
Hi.
Jones, I'm Jim.
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
Thank you.
14 subscribers.
Air correction.
And for example, we are a police fp-log 21, fiscal year 24, our 14, 15, 16, 16, 18, 18,
20, 20, 20, 21, 21, 22, 22, 24, and 24, 26, collective bargaining agreements.
That's a lot, Cindy.
I know what it's so long.
So what we need to do is back in 2014, 2015, 2018, CBA.
There was a spray area.
It just had them in caught.
And so this year, when PD was actually going to try and be or be in some testing, whether
detectives position, an outside person would look at it and realize they're going to be dead.
So this isn't.
It's like, you just dropped off a lot of them.
five, five, seven, five, five.
respectable, five.
Pijinin, we installed October 5.
Five, 15 discussion of
populations.
Item for J. R. Center, Rate Increased and 3%
perpetual annual increase.
ICO instruct, and how he's doing today.
J. R.
Client Ms.
Currently operating upgrades.
We're'reoned back in 2018.
I thought it was six years ago,
No annual perpetual increase and no annual adjustment fees to accommodate higher services that are here in our community.
If you will cost maintenance costs and other operating costs are increasingly increasing at an alarming rate since 2018, our prices have remained the same.
That's a huge impact on the subsidized amount by the MSUA.
Cremation is on the rise and according to the National Pino Director's Association, Cremation is expected to be over 70% by 2030 and almost 80% by 2030.
This will directly affect our bottom line.
How you ask?
At our current rates, basic Cremation is currently only bringing in $400 per burial.
Traditional burials bring you about $850 per burial.
So if we raise that percentage up to 80% you can see that's going to be about a 50% less revenue on average if we don't take action.
GAR currently operates on a budget of $372,000.
The operating budget includes four and a half full-time staff members, our utilities and maintenance and operating costs for our cemetery.
We currently bring in about 23% of the operating budget, which is $85,000.
That leaves 77% being subsidized by the MSUA.
By lowering the subsidized amount we can free up MSUA money so those funds can be utilized in much needed areas around our city.
Today we have a strong desire to align our prices with those in the areas that surround us.
This alignment is going to lower that subsidized amount and correctly undervalued services to our community.
Again, this is going to be a lot of information so I'm just going to try to paraphrase this for you.
On this spreadsheet, I have laid out our current rates,
Glen Abbey rates, our new suggested rates.
The 2022 Wild Dance Study that was performed in 2022
and a benchmark averages.
This spreadsheet was designed to show you just how far behind
GAR Cemetery is compared to our surrounding areas.
Our benchmark area averages in the red column,
our compile the 13 area cemeteries around us,
my Emma, Joplin, Tulsa, Feroen,
Broken Arrow, Nia Show, Web City,
you go to name a few.
We call these 13 areas cemeteries and receive
to break down of all the charges for that they have for their cemeteries.
And we put all their charges on the spreadsheet
and compiled an average of each and every charge.
The average number that you see for these
all the charges that you see over here,
this is the benchmark average for their 13 cemeteries.
Some cherry management team, we met to discuss these averages.
We thought that they looked a little high.
So in order to come up with our new rates,
what we did was we took the average of the benchmark average
and we subtracted 25%.
And that's how we accommodated our new rates.
We didn't want to, you know,
she got on the gate and, you know, just take the average amount.
A lot of that too, as you have to understand,
is some of the benchmark areas that we chose
are larger markets.
And so we really don't compete with that type of market.
So taking that 25% off really brings it down to where we need to be for our area.
We started to continue to improve and update our services.
We've added 15 new fees that will, we will offer to our community.
These are new options and opportunities for new selections and new services.
That other cemeteries are already offering in our surrounding areas.
With this right-knowignment, we want to also provide new affordable services
to our community.
Those new services you will see have highlighted here.
We want members of our community to know that even though we are
performing this rate alignment that we will still offer affordable,
yet beautiful options for them to choose.
We are also requesting that we added 3% annual perpetual increase
to stay competitive in the current market.
This 3% annual increase will also keep us from remaining stagnant in the future
and keep us with that moment to moving forward.
So I can't have broke this down on this brush.
She's in a chart for you guys can see the kind of compare the what our current rates are and what we're asking for
for
the next fiscal year
So the top spreadsheet shows actual numbers. These are not averages. This is our actual deposit amount
From July to October 2023. If you focus on the red dollars amount, those red dollars are going to be
new revenue for ice going forward. So we'll add those to the deposit amount and you'll get those new
totals in the new rates over there on the last column. If I average those numbers, it's about $9,000 a month
or $108,000 a last year that we could have recapped if we would have done it last year.
Below you can see the blue bars, the blue bars, that's what we're currently asking. Those are our current
and our yellow bars are what we hope to approve for next year
to bring in for GAR. As you can see we have a lot of revenue opportunities out there.
This is a chart that shows that we currently are operating and bringing in our revenue and about 85,000.
Remember that's only about 23% of our operating budget. If we do the rating increase, we have a potential
of adding an additional $14,000 on to that. Bring our total $293,725 for a year.
That will drop the MSU subsidy from 77% down to almost 50%. So that'll allow those funds to be used elsewhere.
In closing, we hope you see the values and the importance of raising the rates. I don't like to see it as a
rate increase. I like to see it as a rate alignment because we're just asking to align with the
other cemeteries in our local areas. Thank you. Angela, can you talk briefly about bringing the
other two funeral homes in and talking to them about, you know, because they came up with an idea about
doing groups and there was some pushback from them, so we said, okay, we won't do that, but like,
what about doing this and so if you'll kind of talk about that. So one of the ideas that we had was to do
headstones there at the cemetery, help families with headstones. As, you know, we are part of the
city so we didn't want to step on any of the toes of the funeral home. So we reached out to them just to kind of
get their thoughts and things of that nature and they have a little bit of pushback and I believe they call
it up with you guys. So we're not with them.
join us and kind of writing in my self, met with them just to kind of go over our thoughts
and what we had in mind. They had a lot of other points. It was a wonderful meeting.
I think we've kind of decided to not necessarily, you know, not do it, but we've kind
of tabled it for now, just, you know, because of the points they did bring out.
So, you know, some of the concerns that they had was, especially being a city,
we're always in the line line. If anything was to happen to the stone or we must
it up, you know, you could have pending lawsuits and, of course, you know, we don't
want to stay far away from that. So, that's one thing that, you know,
we wanted to make sure that we address. We are already not responsible, you know,
you know, perhaps not at the cemetery. So, is what we say.
Now, we're not responsible, you know, if anything happens that they would have to replace those,
so, you know, it's, we don't want to kind of be on both sides of it,
not being responsible for it, but yet we're offering you that service.
So, I think, you know, that's something that we can just table for now.
I have a lot of great ideas. So, I'm never at a lack of ideas.
So, I do have a lot of revenue that we could potentially bring in in other ways and other forms.
So, we've just kind of, that's that side.
I just thought it was a good meeting, you know, we sent it out. They said, hey, can you not, you know,
do this service? Okay, that's it. You know, we won't get into that business, but, you know, hey, they kind of talked about, you know,
maybe you can't raise some revenues because you know, obviously, one of them owns a site.
And so, we started my third feed, it's compared to our feeds and just them.
So, that was a good meeting, you know, with those business owners and everything.
And their feeds are almost double our feed.
So, I mean, we really are lacking pretty far behind when it comes to, you know, making sure that, you know,
not that we're saying competitive that we're not selling ourselves short.
I have two questions, then.
The one or four, like, the citizens that come to you for help with this?
Yes. Is there, is there, is there, is there, is there an opportunity for payment plan,
something to help people that are financially struggling?
I love that you brought that out.
So, when I first started out with the cemetery, it's a project that is very dear to my heart for those who are struggling
and need some type of assistance.
I have spoke to Kevin Browning.
We are in the process of putting, you know, some things together that we have to get over to legal for review.
It's definitely a process of not something that we can...
And so, but I would love to start a payment plan, obviously you can't use this space until it's paying for it.
But I hate to compare it to like Rinnis Center.
That type of business does well for our community, especially for people of medial income or below.
So, I think that it would be something that you should definitely visit in the future.
And it is on my list for sales.
And what about your plans for the additional revenue?
I mean, it's like it's like it's like, what are your plans to use in the store?
So, we are in the process of currently looking at a colabarian with an oceawary.
And I don't know if you guys know what an oceawary is.
But an oceawary is a big colabarian that has a hollowed out inside.
And it has like this door that opens with a little slide to go down into the center of it.
The center of the oceawary will hold an additional 600 people per main.
So, when you buy the colabarian, you're not only buying the colabarian, you're buying an oceawary,
since that allows for additional revenue.
When we looked at the possible numbers for the additional revenue, it's like $1.4 million that we can recoup just from purchasing one of these colabarians with an oceawary.
The oceawary also will provide a low, a low cost option to our citizens.
Because it does only require a soft bag in order to go down into the container itself.
Those are a lot of words that I've never heard.
It's going to be honest with you.
But it did Google them, and they are real for those that are interested in knowing.
It's so possible actually.
Are you looking for us though?
We brought this to you as a presentation.
If you're not an oceawary, we'll come back to the next one.
I'd rather wait.
Thank you.
I need to learn how to spell Oceawary.
There's no H in it.
That's for you.
16 ordered CC 2020-24-01 adding section 16 that's 31 and so on and pull fees are equal to
Municipal the turn 16 parks to code the ordinances providing severability
Providing for conflicting provisions
Rebellion all conflicting ordinances and establishing the effective date and the creases were in full fees
So meeting our two ago
We had a discussion with Kevin about praising the
Then council approved it in concept that I remember and this is just effectuating
I'll make a motion. I'll. Second I'll set.
17 is emergency
Clause
same ordinance. We just bring so without the emergency
Open the pool these schedule and 30 days from now switch to
the new fees
Mercer two per
18 mayor's home nation to point dust of heaven to the M. I PFA replacing Brad Williams
Tronderex by 11 724
19 mayor's home nation to point college zones to the MIMA industrial public facilities authority
M. I PFA replacing Dwayne Sunberg turn to expire 11 724
Are you awake right there?
Mayor's nomination to point Bo Reese to the MIMA downtown redevelopment authority M. DRA turn to expire 8 29 24
I thought we was pretty
Motion to approve second
Hi, total
Hi
budget work sessions
So yes, sir, so
Mayor and the pool we're looking at
I'm seeing you guys as thoughts and ideas.
We're looking at doing budget work sessions
at 20th and the 21st, possibly.
We have the, you know, being cognizant of everyone's time.
We have the meeting already scheduled for the 20th.
So we would have to, you know,
ask staff to have a small agenda and then do the meeting.
There's also, we have Larry Gillay from SGR coming down.
So we were going to see maybe what the thoughts are,
maybe having a meeting before an earlier meeting
to meet with SGR.
We had to fit in with the MDRA because we had the MDRA meeting.
There if we had to fit in in, but, you know,
we, with SGR an executive session and then have the regular meeting at six.
Well, those on the 20th, yes, sir.
And then we would, we would schedule the 20th and 21st,
because sometimes we've had two meetings, two days worth of meetings for about just
and then sometimes we would just agree with it and then one.
I'm just to have that in case the board wanted to come back on the 21st.
I'm budgetary talking like an evening like from six to five and then whatever.
Yes.
Then you said the SGR would be before.
So you're talking about it.
Yes.
And then what everybody's thoughts were like we did like 4.30 or 5.
Cindy, think an hour would be enough.
How would you do it for a five?
Would those step in an interview?
About eight or six.
So five to six?
Yeah.
About six.
About that.
Yeah.
But where are you open for anything?
I mean, just a ton of them.
Just a ton of them.
You know, we're usually five.
Yeah.
Start four.
Parts.
Are you thinking six?
Yes, sir.
Six and nine or so.
Yeah.
But that is if we need it.
Four and four.
So it just depends.
And then obviously we would meet again.
You know, we could even have something on the agenda on the 28th.
You know, after the holiday, we have a work study.
We could talk about it then too.
And obviously we would have the presentation of the message and everything in the course meeting
in June.
So June 3rd, we had about.
Jill, what does it get to about June 3rd?
We have a bit of a time present for our meeting in June.
So that gives you.
So you're talking about the 20th.
20th, the 21st, and 28th, just about the 20th, yeah the 20th and the 21st and the 28th would be if we have a work session or whatever.
So if you don't need it then we wouldn't have any discounts of the work session or whatever.
So what you might be some people gone because of the holiday.
So that's the amount of that going to work for you that will be good.
The 20th and 21st will be great the 28th.
Well if we don't do the 28th we would always do the third right.
Yeah.
Because that would be us one more meeting.
Yes.
And we can call it a special meeting in between there or whatever.
So we talked about maybe doing it at the Coleman.
I mean that's like the nicest facility the city has.
You know the budget meetings.
I mean we have pizza or something to serve.
Yeah.
So, you know we've done it before in the staff room.
But I think I think the Coleman's beautiful.
So that's why I kind of didn't even want to.
Yeah.
So.
Okay.
All right.
So we would probably decide what he knows.
We would have, you know, executive session here upstairs with SGR and then we would come
week close there and just go to the Coleman.
On the 20th we'd have to do five because then if you're a man, four to five.
And then five to six.
This is your meeting.
And six.
Right.
Just get a meeting.
And then they get into the budget.
Yeah.
But that's all here.
Right.
That's all here.
Where are you?
The budget would be.
Well the meeting.
The city council meeting.
And the budget meeting.
The next year meeting.
What'd be here?
It's for a meeting.
Look at this.
And we'll just have we wanted to move it back to like start at six,
15.
Yes.
Okay.
So we need to be able to do that.
If you guys would like to do that.
If we could.
But no.
I mean like start at five.
But then, you know, getting down with SGR at six, 15.
And then this.
You know, start at a thing.
The.
Yep.
Just trying to work with everyone's schedule.
Well, I mean, I think everybody's not put on schedule.
So just.
Just get a little more to work out where we can get prepared there.
Okay.
Sounds good.
Twenty-two other business meeting with the Brisbane since both of this agenda.
Twenty-three staff reports.
Twenty-four American Council Community Announcements.
Let's say the Arts Council did the best we'll down down.
It was great.
is a little windy and then worried about rain.
And they asked them, if there's canceling in the class
of me, because it was a rain.
But it turned out really good.
The mirror was turned out really nice.
And it brought South Maine in.
I don't think we've done South Maine in the wall.
But South Maine started to come alive.
I think the Kylo here, she's made a mission of hers
to bring South Maine back to life in the mirror.
It really good.
So it was good time to have her.
That was a great turn.
I was just keep there to do ever get the sea still here.
No, I'm just hoping we'd have that.
How many people showed up?
Oh.
Drusting at that?
The data on how many people showed up?
So the last number is that we get show,
somewhere, 13 inches, you know, how many people?
And I think the painting weather caps, people, what?
Yeah, yeah, really.
But it might have been there or the ones.
So good stuff.
They'll do a good job on that.
So we had some volunteers.
There's a continuous downtown.
That looks really good.
A lot of pots are full on.
If you've seen them, check them out if you haven't.
But we got the Petunian district around here with that.
We can't, we can't, we can't, we can't do Rose district.
It's not like that.
So we're the Petunian district here.
And she's gone.
She's at right there.
She's the...
She's just stepped out.
But I learned all about bubblegum Petunius from Jenny.
I never heard of them before.
But that tastes like bubblegum, I don't know.
They are edible, look.
Yeah, I've heard that.
How'd you know that?
Prove it then.
Yeah, he's going to bring it.
That's what we're going to serve them on the budget.
Yeah.
Oh, Oklahoma was going to call them.
Is it over now?
Yeah.
I hope you guys want to see it, because it was a really good show.
We have for a thousand people here, way more talented to make, because the people get
saying they did a good job.
That's what's going to come in, you know, my whole thing in the government did a good job.
Getting that put on.
The seven choppers had it downtown, they were really good event.
The vendors that came in, and our colonel chop people, our colonel chop people, said they
did a month worth of sales in one night.
And Kudos to Keaton, our team from being that put on.
There was a great thing downtown.
A lot of people down there.
And I think the...
Excellent.
I think the vendors that came in, and my interactions building, I think they're requesting
for us to do this at once a month.
We're trying to find another available space that's written in anybody's got something that
would be great.
So if they pop up something and they become a regular thing.
Of course, we'd love to have it.
in the downtown area because then they go eat it, you know, you get fellas and get some
of the other places too, but our girls that are doing the downtown, and she left so we came
back on her, but Jenny and her team have been a great job. They're really coming up from outside
of the box ideas, and they're talking to other communities where other communities are doing,
trying to make it work here, so they're going to get job. We've got to really get team down there,
so I'm excited to see what they do, so I think that's all I have in the middle of the day.
So you may have your communications. I just want to just tell the board, I don't know if
everybody's aware about what we sit, the electric crew, to Wagner, Friday and Saturday,
and I've been restored power to a lot of different areas. Something I want to thank the board
for, like, previous boards, and I really see her, and then, you know, her current board. We have a lot of
equipment that a lot of cities don't have because we do so much of our stuff in-house, and so the board
has allows us to purchase that, and I mean, Wagner was like totally impressed. We have a track machine,
they can go anywhere, the pitfalls that because, you know, the poles never break, where they're easy to
get to, they don't break in areas, they're not. So they had them, you know, feeding a couple of facilities,
they're out in the middle of wheat fields, and there were things like that. They couldn't get to, you know,
so I mean, we took our track machine down there, and they were impressed and they were working out
exactly a few days in a row, and they were impressed with the crews, and just those needs. So I do
appreciate that. I think what I'm realizing, you know, you know, our rates do go into by this equipment,
you know, every day, so I mean, it's easy to build a good help with them, and something I don't really think
of a lot, but like, whenever the way in their city of administrators, like, oh my gosh, my gosh,
my gosh, like, you gotta get us one of these, like, it is like the needs things. I appreciate that.
I want to jump back, I got one more for God. The other night during the flood event,
we had a water rescue, and my and fire, okay, so enough about those guys. I was worried sick.
Tyler was message me, and I knew how that water was running, and our guys were out there trying to save
somebody, but there was a homeless man that was caught up in the tree, been there for a couple of days,
the yellow for help, and finally somebody heard him. He was in the middle of nowhere in the woods,
a couple of our firefighters, Bullard, and McBride. We've gotten the boat, we're not the body.
They couldn't get there because of all the wood and stuff in the way, and the firefighters,
Bullard, bailed off, and swam to this guy, and it was quite a distance, but he needs to be commended
for that, because he, he put his own life at risk to go save somebody else, and you're not going to find
wearing people that are willing to do that, but Chris said it was just, he was in a choir about her boat,
it's his job, he's going to get it done. So, who knows to him, and actually it's all of her part of
our department, because there are teams, and the other departments that came to help, one of the other
was lots of other departments, there's oil. So the drone, that's for the drone, but the infrared,
we're able to locate where he was at.
You said bowl of water and swam for about half a mile back up in there to get to the guy in the in the middle of the night
Yeah, in the dark. So
So I said
Yeah, that would have been that I would have been quite scary, but
Chris and bowl just did it
Yeah
So now
26 this mean when I'll be continue to count chambers and make it mean the staff room purpose of the executive session
Then we'll come back out
All right